var movies = [
    {
        id: 0,
        question: "&#x1F427;  &#x1F603; &#x1F463;",
        answers:{
            a: "FINDING YOUR FEET",
            b: "MARCH OF THE PENGUINS",
            c: "HAPPY FEET",
            d: "PENGUINS OF MADAGASCAR",
        },
        correct: "HAPPY FEET",
        letter: "c",
    },

    {   id: 1,
        question: "&#x1F5E1; &#x1F355; &#x1F42D; &#x1F422",
        answers:{
            a: "THE SECRET LIFE OF PETS",
            b: "TEENAGE MUTANT NINJA TURTLES",
            c: "A TURTLES TALE",
            d: "TURTLE, THE INCREDIBLE JOURNEY",
        },
        correct: "TEENAGE MUTANT NINJA TURTLES",
        letter: "b",
    },



    {   id: 2,
        question: "&#x1F46A; &#x1F6EB; &#x1F631; &#x1F3E1; &#x1F384;",
        answers:{
            a: "HOME ALONE",
            b: "FLY AWAY HOME",
            c: "FAMILY FLIGHT",
            d: "THE NIGHTMARE BEFORE CHRISTMAS",
        },
        correct: "HOME ALONE",
        letter: "a",
           
    },

    {   
        id: 3,
        question: "&#x1F62E; &#x1F417; &#x1F50E; &#x1F4BC; &#x1F4DA;",
        answers:{
            a: "JUMANJI",
            b: "FANTASTIC BEASTS AND WHERE TO FIND THEM",
            c: "POKÃˆMON",
            d: "SCOOBY-DOO",
        },
        correct: "FANTASTIC BEASTS AND WHERE TO FIND THEM",
        letter: "b",
           
    },

    {   
        id: 4,
        question: "&#x1F699; &#x1F4A8; &#x23F3; ",
        answers:{
            a: "FAST AND FURIOUS",
            b: "CARS",
            c: "FAST FIVE",
            d: "RUSH HOUR",
        },
        correct: "RUSH HOUR",
        letter: "d",
           
    },


    {
        id: 5,
        question: "&#x1F3F0; &#x1F3D4; &#x1F46D; &#x2603&#xFE0F;",
        answers:{
            a: "ICE PRINCESS",
            b: "JACK FROST",
            c: "FROZEN",
            d: "THE PRINCESS DIARIES",
        },
        correct: "FROZEN",
        letter: "c",
           
    },

    {
        id: 6,
        question: "&#x1F469&#x1F3FF; &#x1F469&#x1F3FF; &#x1F469&#x1F3FF; &#x1F680;",
        answers:{
            a: "HIDDEN FIGURES",
            b: "DREAM GIRLS",
            c: "MISSION TO MARS",
            d: "SPARKLE",
        },
        correct: "HIDDEN FIGURES",
        letter: "a",
           
    },

    {
        id: 7,
        question: "&#x1F467; &#x1F49A; &#x1F608; &#x1F497; &#x1F384;",
        answers:{
            a: "THE NIGHTMARE BEFORE CHRISTMAS",
            b: "THE GRINCH",
            c: "ELF",
            d: "GREMLINS",
        },
        correct: "THE GRINCH",
        letter: "b",
           
    },

    {
        id: 8,
        question: "&#x1F466&#x1F3FC; &#x1F570; &#x1F511; &#x1F4D4 &#x1F682;",
        answers:{
            a: "HUGO",
            b: "THE POLAR EXPRESS",
            c: "SOURCE CODE",
            d: "MURDER ON THE ORIENT EXPRESS",
        },
        correct: "HUGO",
        letter: "a",
           
    },

    {
        id: 9,
        question: "&#x1F601; &#x1F49B; &#x1F62D; &#x1F499; <br/> &#x1F620; &#x2764&#xFE0F; &#x1F61F; &#x1F49C; <br/> &#x1F637; &#x1F49A;",
        answers:{
            a: "SNOW WHITE AND THE SEVEN DWARFS",
            b: "POWER RANGERS",
            c: "INSIDE OUT",
            d: "CHARLIE AND THE CHOCOLATE FACTORY",
        },
        correct: "INSIDE OUT",
        letter: "c",
           
    },

    {
        id: 10,
        question: "&#x1F47D; &#x260E&#xFE0F; &#x1F3E0; &#x1F6B2; &#x1F319;",
        answers:{
            a: "MEN IN BLACK",
            b: "10 CLOVERFIELD LANE",
            c: "ARRIVAL",
            d: "ET",
        },
        correct: "ET",
        letter: "d",
           
    },

    {
        id: 11,
        question: "&#x1F469&#x1F3FB; &#x1F306; &#x1F373;  &#x1F48D",
        answers:{
            a: "ROMAN HOLIDAY",
            b: "MY FAIR LADY",
            c: "THE ENGAGEMENT RING",
            d: "BREAKFAST AT TIFFANY'S",
        },
        correct: "BREAKFAST AT TIFFANY'S",
        letter: "d",
           
    },

    {
        id: 12,
        question: "&#x1F437; &#x1F33A; &#x1F334; &#x1F30A;",
        answers:{
            a: "LILO & STITCH",
            b: "BABE",
            c: "MOANA",
            d: "CHARLOTTE'S WEB",
        },
        correct: "MOANA",
        letter: "c",
    },

    {
        id: 13,
        question: "&#x1F981; &#x1F682; &#x1F1EE&#x1F1F3;  &#x27A1&#xFE0F; &#x1F1E6&#x1F1FA; &#x1F62D;",
        answers:{
            a: "LION KING",
            b: "SLUMDOG MILLIONAIRE",
            c: "LIFE OF PI",
            d: "LION",
        },
        correct: "LION",
        letter: "d",
    },

    {
        id: 14,
        question: "&#x1F6AB; &#x1F57A; &#x1F483; &#x1F6AB; &#x1F3A4; &#x1F3B6;",
        answers:{
            a: "LA LA LAND",
            b: "HAIRSPRAY",
            c: "GREASE",
            d: "FOOTLOOSE",
        },
        correct: "FOOTLOOSE",
        letter: "d",
    },

    {
        id: 15,
        question: "&#x1F430; &#x1F694; &#x1F98A; &#x1F454;",
        answers:{
            a: "SECRET LIFE OF PETS",
            b: "DR. DOLITTLE",
            c: "ZOOTOPIA",
            d: "PETER RABBIT",
        },
        correct: "ZOOTOPIA",
        letter: "c",
    },

    {
        id: 16,
        question: "&#x2B1B; &#x1F577; &#x1F916; &#x1F468; <br/> &#x1F621; &#x1F34F; &#x1F6E1&#xFE0F; &#x1F1FA&#x1F1F8; <br/> &#x1F528; &#x26A1;",
        answers:{
            a: "JUSTICE LEAGUE",
            b: "THE AVENGERS",
            c: "TRANSFORMERS",
            d: "POWER RANGERS",
        },
        correct: "THE AVENGERS",
        letter: "b",
    },

    {
        id: 17,
        question: "&#x1F470; &#x1F935; &#x1F3A4; &#x1F3B6;",
        answers:{
            a: "WEDDING CRASHERS",
            b: "MAMA MIA",
            c: "THE WEDDING SINGER",
            d: "BRIDESMAIDS",
        },
        correct: "THE WEDDING SINGER",
        letter: "c",
    },

    {
        id: 18,
        question: "&#x1F47B; &#x1F47B; &#x1F6AB; &#x1F392; &#x1F52B",
        answers:{
            a: "BEETLEJUICE",
            b: "GOOSEBUMPS",
            c: "CASPER",
            d: "GHOSTBUSTERS",
        },
        correct: "GHOSTBUSTERS",
        letter: "d",
    },

    {
        id: 19,
        question: "&#x1F436; &#x1F6B2; &#x1F32A&#xFE0F; &#x1F3DA&#xFE0F; &#x1F460; &#x1F916; &#x1F981; &#x2747&#xFE0F;",
        answers:{
            a: "MALEFICENT",
            b: "OZ THE GREAT AND POWERFUL",
            c: "THE WIZARD OF OZ",
            d: "ALICE IN WONDERLAND",
        },
        correct: "THE WIZARD OF OZ",
        letter: "c",
    },
   
    
]

//global variables
var myTimer, letter, num, timeLeft, y;
var unanswered = 0;
var correct = 0;
var incorrect = 0;
var qCount = 0;

// var questionTitle = "Can you guess the movie from the emojis?"

$(document).on('click', '.start', function(){
    // randomizes the array of movies
    movies.sort(function() { return 0.5 - Math.random() });
    $(this).hide();
    $('#ticketContainer, #filmContainer, #qNum, #timer, #emoji').show();
    $('#results').hide();
    currentQuestion(qCount);
    
});

function currentQuestion(count){
    // adds question number to the side ot the ticket stub
    $('#qNum').html("Q. No. " + (qCount+1) + " / 10")
    $('.choice').removeClass('correctAnswer incorrectAnswer');

    // adds the hov class that causes the answer choice to hover
    $('.choice').addClass('hov');

    y = true;

    // displays the question if there are questions left to answer
    if (count < (movies.length/2)){
        timeLeft = 10;
        $('#timer').text("Time Remaining: " + timeLeft + ' seconds');
        myTimer = setInterval(countdown, 1000);
        $('#emoji').html(movies[count].question);
        $('#a').html(movies[count].answers.a);
        $('#b').html(movies[count].answers.b);
        $('#c').html(movies[count].answers.c);
        $('#d').html(movies[count].answers.d);
        letter = movies[count].letter;

    }
    //after all questions have been shown then show the Trivia Game Complete screen
    else{
        $('#qNum, #timer, #emoji, #filmContainer').hide();
        $('#results, #playAgain').show();
        $("#playAgain").css('display', 'flex');
        $('#corNum').html(correct);
        $('#incorNum').html(incorrect);
        $('#unNum').html(unanswered);
        // randomizes the array of movies
        movies.sort(function() { return 0.5 - Math.random() });


        qCount = 0;
        unanswered = 0;
        correct = 0;
        incorrect = 0;

    }

}

// countdown function that either has text showing the Time Remaining in seconds or Time's Up if no answer choice was selected
function countdown() {
    $('#timer').removeClass('correctHeader incorrectHeader').css('color', 'black');
    if (timeLeft == 1) {
        clearTimeout(myTimer);
        $('#timer').text("Time's Up!")
        // $("input[type=radio]").attr('disabled', true);
        $('.choice').removeClass('hov');
        noAnswerSelected();

    } else {
        //timeLeft is decreased before displaying the timer text which fixed the lag.
        timeLeft--;
        $('#timer').text("Time Remaining: " + timeLeft + ' seconds');
        
        if(timeLeft <= 5){
            $('#timer').css('color', 'red'); 
        }

    }
}

// if no answer was selected by the user
function noAnswerSelected(){ 
    $("#"+letter).addClass('correctAnswer');
    unanswered ++;
    qCount++;
    setTimeout(function(){
        currentQuestion(qCount)
    }, 4000);
    
}



